geeksmate.io 2019-04-06

# Privacy Policy

What information do we collect?  
Thank you for visiting our Privacy Policy page. Here, we are to mention what information do we collect. We call this information "Personally Identifiable Information" (also commonly referred to as personal data). This can be understood as all data that can be used to identify you. The following types of data about you may be collected on your visits to our website:

  * Your IP address;

  * Your operating system and browser software used to access our website;  
story related information which you read;

  * Your demographics (Country, City, Language etc);

  * Your unique numeric identification;

  * Your device information and cookies;

  * In the event you contact us by email, we may keep a record of that correspondence; such record may include, apart from your email address the Personally Identifiable 

  * Information that you will include in the communication.

How information collected is used

Use of Personal Data

  * We collect and use your Personally Identifiable Information for the following legitimate business purposes:

  * For general data analysis and to run our website better;

  * For generating statistics and measuring web traffic and to understand the popularity of specific areas of our website;

  * For identifying usage trends and expanding our business activities;

  * For building higher quality and providing a better user experience by tracking the behavior of our users;

  * For complying with applicable legal requirements and satisfying requests by governmental and supervisory authorities;

  * For identifying and preventing fraud.

With whom we share information

Except as set forth in this Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, we will not disclose any of your Personally Identifiable Information. We may disclose and otherwise use Personally Identifiable Information as described below.

Affiliates

We share your Personally Identifiable Information with our affiliates — companies that control, are controlled by, or are under common control with Vatsana Technologies Pvt Ltd.

Our Partners

We allow third party advertising companies including carefully selected ad networks and business partners (referred to as "Our Partners"), to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [Click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

Service Providers

Your information may be collected by entities that provide services to us, including companies that deliver web analytics, data processing, data enhancement, and customer insights, advertising, email distribution, and other services.

Other Parties (when required by law or as necessary to protect our services). We may disclose your information (including Personally Identifiable Information) to other parties in order to 

1\. protect our legal rights or property, the legal rights or property of our affiliates, and sites or services we offer;  
2\. protect the rights, safety, and security of our users, ourselves, or any other person or entity;  
3\. prevent fraud (or for risk management purposes);  
in order to comply with or respond to the law or legal process or a request for cooperation by a governmental or supervisory authority, whether or not legally required.  
4\. how the data might get transferred cross-border  
5\. usually, we maintain centralized servers and systems in Europe and may maintain servers and systems elsewhere. These servers and systems are managed by us or on our behalf, or by our affiliates.

In the event of transfer and processing of your Personally Identifiable Information outside the EEA, we will make sure that the information receives the same level of protection as if it remained within the EEA using the EU Commission approved Standard Contractual Clauses, or by relying on certification schemes such as the EU-US Privacy Shield.

How Secure is your information

We use commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your Personally Identifiable Information from misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction in accordance with the requirements of applicable laws.

How can you exercise your rights under GDPR?

Considering you are individual browsing from the EU/EEA, where the General Data Protection Regulations apply, you can exercise rights related to your data by contacting us via contact details at the bottom of the page.

How can we use information for personal advertising

The information collected by Our Partners is used to analyze trends, understand user activities and gather demographic information to enable, manage and develop their personalized ads and related services. This type of information does not identify you personally and, typically, is aggregated with other data to create segments – groups of users and general interest categories that are inferred based on a range of factors.

How we protect privacy for children

Our content is aimed at a general audience. We do not knowingly target, collect, use or share information that could reasonably be used to identify children under the age of 15 without prior parental consent or consistent with applicable law. By using our service you confirm that you either are of legal age or have an applicable consent.

How we use external links

Our website may display links to websites of third party content providers, other than Our Partners. We do not disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to third parties without obtaining your consent specifically permitting such disclosure. We do not endorse and are not responsible for the privacy practices and content of such third parties. We encourage you to review their privacy policies to understand how they collect and process your Personally Identifiable Information.

How often do we make changes in our Privacy Policy?

We may amend or update this Privacy Policy from time to time. So, one should check it periodically where changes are made, we will post the revised Policy here with an updated effective date.

Cookies and Target Advertising

We may use small pieces of information placed on your browser, known as “cookies”, to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience. We may use cookies to determine what advertisements you see, control the sequence of advertisements and make sure you don't see the same advertisement too many times. For contests or sweepstakes, we may use cookies in order to track your progress and the number of entries in some promotions. For polls or surveys, we may use cookies to help ensure that an individual can't vote more than once on a particular question or issue. We may use cookies along with pixels, web beacons (which are usually small, transparent graphic images), operating system and device information and navigational data like Uniform Resource Locators (URL), to gather information regarding the date and time of your visit, the features and information for which you searched and viewed, the email you opened, or on which advertisements you clicked. Companies Refinery29 works with may also use cookies for understanding Web usage patterns of users who see advertisements on the Website. We do not store personal information in any cookies on your computer.

Cookies can be removed by following your Internet browser's directions usually within the help menu. In order to use certain features of the Website, your web browser must accept cookies. If you choose to disable cookies, some aspects of the Website may not work properly, and you may not be able to access the Website.

We believe that advertising is more interesting to you when it is relevant. Accordingly, we customize the advertisements that you see based upon: (i) geographic location information, which we may determine through your IP address or other ways; (ii) data we receive from third parties and/or; (iii) your visits on the Website or use of other services (commonly referred to as behavioral advertising or interest-based advertising). We may use your personal information to deliver customized advertising to you on this Website, on other websites and on other digital and offline media channels. We may use third-party vendors to connect information collected on the Website (such as IP addresses, geolocation, cookie-related data, and other information described above) with information collected from other websites, devices, and media channels and then show you advertising based on this combined information. The advertisement may appear when you are visiting a different section of the Website or another website, device or media channel.

If you would like more information about behavioral advertising and to know your choices with respect to it, please visit www.aboutads.info/choices. Many vendors that engage in behavioral advertising participate in the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) and abide by NAI and/or DAA principles. If you wish to opt out of participating in advertising programs conducted by NAI and DAA members or learn more about the NAI and DAA, please go to the NAI Opt-Out website or DAA Ad Choice Page and follow the instructions. After you opt-out, you will still see advertisements, but the advertising may not be as relevant to your interests. If you change your computer, change your browser or delete your cookies, you will need to renew your opt-out. For opt-out options specific to Google Analytics, please visit tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout. If you delete your cookies or upgrade your browser after having opted out, you will need to opt out again. If you use multiple browsers or devices, you will need to execute this opt-out on each browser or device.

Advertisers or other third parties on the Website may also engage in behavioral advertising and use cookies and web beacons in the manner described above. We do not control these advertisers or other parties' use of cookies or web beacons or what they do with the information they collect.

We may use Facebook to deliver ads on the Website. Facebook may use the information you share on Facebook and information gathered from your use of other websites and apps to deliver ads to you. To learn more about this type of advertising and your choices about it, visit www.facebook.com/about/ads.

Our Website is currently not set up to respond or process web browser “Do Not Track” (“DNT”) signals We do adhere to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising of the Digital Advertising Alliance (for more information click here).

Information We Receive From Third Parties. We may combine online and/or offline information received from third parties with the information we have already collected from you via our Website or services. The third party information is used for a variety of purposes including to verify other information about you (e.g., verify your mailing address to send you requested products or services), to conduct research, and to enhance the content and advertising we provide to you.
